The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Twelfth Episode
The Prince and the Gypsy
The Ragged Prince
Ah, Sapphire! Good morning.
Good morning, Tink.
Hey, wait!
Who are you people?
Please forgive my companion Gem for being so rude just now.
I'm just glad you and this gentleman weren't hurt.
Don't worry about it! As you can see—
Ow, that hurts!
Unbelievable...
Hey! How can you stand there laughing after our friend got badly hurt?!
Where did he go?
Huh, he's pretty strong.
Of course he is.
He's the Prince of Silverland. Wait, a prince?
He doesn't look like much for a prince.
You look pretty shabby yourself.
Can't be helped.
We're gypsies, after all.
Gypsies?
What's a Gypsy?
We're folks who travel all year round—singing, doing magic tricks, and stealing stuff.
My name's Gem.
And what about your father and mother?
My mom and dad died a long time ago.
Must be nice to be a prince.
Just once, I'd like to boss people around in a place like that.
Shall I let you?
Don't tease me.
How could you do that just as a favor for a Gypsy?
Oh, but I can!
How?
How's this?
What's the point of making a face like that?
Wow, you two look identical!
Right now, I'm reading a book called The Prince and the Pauper.
It's about a prince and a beggar swapping places. See?
So, just like in the book, Gem and I are going to swap places.
Great idea, right?
Hey, Gem!
I haven't even had dinner yet!
Man, he's late. What is he doing?
Whoa, I can't tell which is which!
Gem, make sure you come back here by evening.
Got it?
Okay!
Well then!
Wait! Wait!
Sapphire! Wait!
Yahoo!
Whoa, isn't that Tink?!
Sapphire, help me!
What are you doing here?
The town bullies caught me!
Well, well! Are you a friend of his?
Hey! Picking on the weak isn't right!
What?! You've got some nerve!
Where did you come from?!
Over there!
All right, you weirdo!
If you want him back, you'll have to duel me!
A duel?
Come on!
You big neighborhood bully!
All right, here I come!
You little brat!
Help!
How strange!
It's a tie!
Let me try again!
All right!
Okay!
All right, watch this!
Here I go!
Yah! Hello there!
Yah!
I'm not... I mean, I am the Prince!
Show some respect!
Uh, no, wait... hey, I know you, pal!
What's going on?
Uh, does my voice sound strange?
I-I've caught a cold!
Help!
Sapphire, look how late it's getting...
That's right, we must head back!
Whoa, wait for me!
Sapphire!
Forgive me!
Water, please!
Stop it!
Well now, Gem, you've got some nerve kicking me.
I thought your friends had abandoned you and left.
Gem, I shall tell your fortune.
An ill-omened star hangs over you.
Let's see... one, five, eight... thirteen cards.
Gem, your star is...
This one!
My, Gem... your card says you're a girl!
My, I've really gotten old.
I'm already dead!
Brother Gem!
Welcome home, Brother.
Your dinner is over there, Brother.
Hold it!
You didn't earn a single coin today. Got it?
So you're only getting half a portion.
Remember that.
Then, who are...
Who are you?
I'm Gem's sister.
I won't tell anyone, so please tell me.
Where is my brother?
Is he not coming back?
Well, for various reasons, I swapped places with your brother.
I am the prince of Silverland.
Wow, so you're a prince!
It's Liz, the little bird.
Liz, you've come back too?
It's already evening, isn't it?
Oh no!
It's gotten so dark already.
Hurry, or it'll get dark.
Ah, Gem!
Hey, Tink!
The castle is so boring.
Must be nice.
This is the last of the potion that reveals whether Sapphire is a boy or a girl.
Make no mistakes this time, men!
Coat your blade with it. It turns blue on a man, and red on a woman.
And bright yellow on an egg!
Attack!
Intruders!
Stand back!
I am the Prince!
And it's the Prince we have business with!
We got him!
We did it!
Curse it!
We haven't searched here yet!
Have no fear, it is Nylon. I've driven off the intruder.
Please, lift your head.
Is that so?
He's a man!
What are you talking about? Of course I'm a man!
Come, Gem is waiting. Let's hurry!
No, no, Gem.
You won't escape that easily!
Drag them all away!
Nylon, say that again!
Yes, my lord.
So Prince Sapphire really is a boy...
Nonsense! That fool's potion must have failed!
No, no, Lord Duralumin.
The potion's effect will never fail, even if the sun rises in the west. Indeed.
How can this be?!
To think Sapphire was a boy all along!
Hey, Nylon!
Yes, Sir.
In that case, our last resort is to kill Sapphire...
Kill him... Yes.
But those three assassins aren't enough.
You've tamed the Gypsies, haven't you?
No!
I wasn't trying to run away!
I intended to bring back the real Gem!
I'm a prince!
If you think I'm lying, bring anyone you want from the castle!
A prince?
Hey, did you all hear that?
Gem's finally lost his mind!
What if it's true?!
Stop laughing!
t's not a lie!
Please, Mr. Ton.
Please forgive my brother!
Forgive him?
He's got some nerve!
Trying to run away when he doesn't even earn his keep—I can't stand it!
Then I'll work in his place!
Work?
Well, fair enough.
All right, I'll give you a job.
Hey, cut Pepper's ropes!
Take this bundle to town and sell it!
What?
Right now?
That's right! If you sell it all by dawn, I'll spare Gem!
That's insane!
Who's going to buy anything this late?!
If you fail, he gets hanged!
Wait for me, Brother! I promise I'll sell it all!
Pepper!
I'm scared!
Mommy! I'm scared! Daddy! Big brother!
Here's the town...
Would anyone like some firewood?
No, thanks.
Would anyone like some...
My firewood...
I need to gather it fast!
Help!
A girl is drowning!
Goro-goro-san Come on, come on, quickly!
Goro-goro-san thank you!
Hold on tight, okay?
Sister!
Father
Mother!
Open your eyes!
Don't... don't die!
After I went through all the trouble to save you!
Please!
Save this child!
What about that Heavenly Father?
At least say something!
Ah!
It's beautiful!
It's gold!
Mother must have given it to me in my dream!
Thank you!
Good for you!
Hey, Gem!
Pepper isn't back yet!
If they're not back by dawn, it's the gallows!
Mr. Ton
Pepper!
Look!
Hey, everyone!
This is gold!
Hey!
I'll cut Gem's rope!
Pepper!
Hey!
Gypsy scum!
This looks important!
Oh boy, oh boy!
Lord Officers!
If it's official castle business!
Then hear my command!
Kill Sapphire!
By order of the castle... for me?
First, Sapphire goes for a walk with Lord Nylon!
That's when we kill him!
Ton!
Go get four men at once!
Got it!
Yah!
Thank you for your service!
Hey!
Everyone, assemble!
Let us do this together!
Men, this is official castle business!
Stay sharp!
Oh no!
Gem is in danger!
Please, Highness!
Save my big brother!
If Big Brother dies, Pepper will die too!
Oh, Lil!
All right!
Do not worry, Pepper!
I, Sapphire, will surely save your brother!
Please!
A morning ride truly is delightful, Your Highness.
It is an honor to accompany you.
Honor is fine, but slow down a bit!
Let us head back to the castle now.
He always rushes off like that.
He went the wrong way!
Help!
Prince!
Help me!
Gem!
I'm coming!
He's here!
- Your Highness!
- Gem
Keep out of my way!
Wait, aren't you Gem?!
What on earth are you doing here?!
Go back!
Get out of here!
I'm sorry, but I can't go back!
Your Highness really is strong.
Gem, what about the assassins?
That pole hit them earlier, so they're knocked out cold over there.
Gem, did you enjoy yourself?
Inside the castle?
It was totally boring in there.
There were always guards watching me.
How about you, Sapphire?
A lot happened on my end, too.
I feel I learned quite a lot from it all.
Farewell, Gem.
Pepper is waiting for you.
Yeah.
Damn it!
That prince was an imposter!
He's an imposter!
An imposter!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if demons come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP